Guide to the Young Women's Christian Associations, Stanford Chapter, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Young Women's Christian Associations, Stanford Chapter, records
1891-1983
SC0287
Young Women's Christian Associations. Stanford Chapter.
65 Linear feet
Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, programs, photographs, and other records.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The YWCA of Stanford University, organized in 1892, was concerned with the special interests of women students; its activities included freshman orientation, student employment service, work with international students, tutoring, and community service projects. The chapter closed in 1983.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, programs, photographs, and other records.
Access Terms
Young Women's Christian Associations. Stanford Chapter.; Women--Education.; Women--Societies and clubs; Young Women's Christian associations --California.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Clippings 1974 (Box 1)
  - Rolled photographs from conferences at Asilomar (Box 1)
  - Eight reels of audio tapes: 1968-69 encounter groups; 1962 talks by Dr. Charles McCoy; and others (Box 1)
  - Files 1960s-1970s on:
    - Endowment Fund (Box 1)
    - Financial Adv. Committee (Box 1)
    - Other misc. files (Box 1)
    - Loose printed items (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of clippings on YWCA divesting in firms doing business with South Africa, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook pages with photographs and clippings 1950s (Box 2)
  - Minutes 1937-39, 1947-49 (Box 2)
  - Clippings 1931-1943 (Box 2)
  - Misc. photos and 3 slides (Box 2)
  - Lists of Board members 1905-1981 (Box 2)
  - Misc. brochures, fliers, etc. (Box 2)
  - Photographs of Strawberry Brunches (Box 3)
  - Newsletter; talks by Eric Hutchinson (Box 3)
  - Ledger 1974 (Box 3)
  - Files on:
    - Strawberry brunches 1950s (Box 3)
    - Divestment (Box 3)
    - Programs (Box 3)
    - Business matters (Box 3)
    - Financial matters (Box 3)
  - Files, 1970s, on:
    - Payroll, endowment, and other financial matters (Box 4)
    - Stanford YWCA history (Box 4)
    - National Board affairs (Box 4)
    - Racism (sources on) (Box 4)
  - Files, 1970s, on:
    - Financial matters (Box 5)
    - United Way - correspondence (Box 5)
    - Personnel files (Box 5)
    - Committees (Box 5)
    - Membership (Box 5)
    - Women's Center (Box 5)
    - Divestment (Box 5)
  - Files, 1970s, on:
    - Finance (Box 6)
    - Convention (Box 6)
    - Various programs (Box 6)
    - Women's Center (Box 6)
    - "Action Audit" (Box 6)
    - Racism (Box 6)
  - Board Minutes, 1975-78 [contents are 1977-79]
    - Endowment (Box 6)
  - Files, 1970s, on:
    - United Way Quarterly Reports, 1974-75 (Box 7)
    - Board retreat 1978 (Box 7)
    - Program Committee (Box 7)
    - Taxes - Bills - Insurance (Box 7)
    - Personnel matters (Box 7)
  - Files, 1960s & 1970s, on:
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
    - Adventures in Friendship 1960s (Box 8)
    - Board training (Box 8)
    - Financial (Box 8)
    - Space (Box 8)
    - Angela Davis 1970 (Box 8)
    - Program statistics (Box 8)
  - Files, 1960-70s, on:
    - Financial matters (incoming and outgoing) (Box 9)
    - United Fund (Box 9)
  - Files, 1960-70s, on:
    - Financial matters (Box 10)
  - Address cards (Box 11)
  - Cancelled Checks 1970s (Box 11)
  - Personnel Files (Box 11)
  - Files, 1960s-70s, on:
    - Adventures in Friendship 1966-67 (Box 12)
    - Various programs, projects, 1960s (Box 12)
    - Program Committee (Box 12)
    - "Y" history (Box 12)
    - Directors Reports, 1957-62 (Box 12)